Welcome. In the last lecture, we successfully create a handy function for us to perform
欢迎。在上一讲中，我们成功地创建了一个方便的函数，为我们执行
capsule trace. And in this lecture, we look at how we can use this to trace for the climbable
胶囊追踪。而在这一讲中，我们将看看如何使用这个函数来追踪可攀登的
surfaces. For that, I'm going to create a new region just above the region for climb
表面。为此，我将创建一个新的区域，就在爬升区域的上方
variables. I'm going to create a new one. So it's going to be pound region. I'm going
变量。我将创建一个新的。所以这将是一个磅状区域。我将
to call this one climb core. And inside of it, I'm going to create a function. It's
称之为爬升核心。在它里面，我将创建一个函数。它是
going to be void. I'm going to call it trace climbable surfaces. And I'm going to create
将会是空的。我将把它称为 "追踪可攀登表面"。然后我将创建
a function definition, paste the function below this region, and I'm going to copy
一个函数定义，把这个函数粘贴到这个区域下面，然后我把这个区域复制到
this region to here. So inside of this function, we'll need to call the function that we just
这个区域到这里。所以在这个函数里面，我们需要调用我们在上一节课中创建的函数
created in the last lecture. So I'm going to paste it in here. And we'll need to fill
在上一节课中创建的函数。所以我要把它粘贴到这里。我们还需要填写
in the trace start and trace end. But how can we get such information? Since we are
追踪开始和追踪结束。但是我们如何才能得到这样的信息呢？因为我们是在
inside of character moving component, we cannot do things like get actor location and rotation.
角色移动组件的内部，我们不能做诸如获得演员位置和旋转的事情。
Well, to solve this issue, there's another variable just for that. So our character movement
好吧，为了解决这个问题，有另一个变量专门用于此。所以我们的角色移动
component inherits from this U moving component. And inside of it, there's a variable is called
组件继承自这个U移动组件。在它的内部，有一个变量叫做
updated component. And you can see from the comment, it says this is the component we
更新组件。你可以从注释中看到，它说这是我们的组件
move and update. So this is the actual component that moves our character. We can use this
移动和更新。所以这就是实际的移动我们的角色的组件。我们可以用这个
to get hold of important information like our characters for vector location and rotation
来获取重要的信息，比如我们的角色的矢量位置和旋转方向
for us to do the calculation we need. So right above this function, I'm going to create a
以便我们进行所需的计算。所以就在这个函数的上方，我将创建一个
variable. It's going to be a const F vector. I'm going to call this one start. We can access
变量。它将是一个Const F向量。我将把这个变量称为 "开始"。我们可以访问
the component updated component directly inside of this class. And we can use the function
直接访问这个类中的更新组件。而且我们可以使用函数
get component locations to get hold of the location of our character. And since we are
get component locations来获取我们角色的位置。由于我们是
detecting the surfaces in front of our character, I'm going to offer some start offset. So it
探测我们角色前面的表面，我将提供一些起始偏移。所以它
will be the component location plus the start offset we need. And for that, I'm going to
将是组件的位置加上我们需要的起始偏移。为此，我将会
create another variable. So it's going to be another const F vector. I'm going to call
创建另一个变量。所以它将是另一个常量F矢量。我将把它称为
this start offset and you'll be our updated component get forward vector. And I'm going
这个起始偏移量将是我们更新后的分量前进矢量。而我将会
to increase its length by 30 units and I'm going to copy this start offset and paste
把它的长度增加30个单位，然后把这个起始偏移量复制并粘贴到
it in here. So this is the start of our capsule trace. And as for the end, I'm going to create
它在这里。所以这是我们的胶囊追踪的开始。至于终点，我将创建
another variable. So it's going to be another const F vector. I'm going to call it end.
另一个变量。所以它将是另一个常数F矢量。我将把它称为结束。
So the end would be the start plus some values. So how capsule trace works in here is you
所以终点将是起点加上一些数值。所以胶囊追踪在这里的工作原理是你
will draw multiple capsules between the start and end we specify in here. And for the end
将在我们指定的起点和终点之间绘制多个胶囊。而对于结束
in here, I'm just going to give it a very small value. So you'll be start plus this
我只是要给它一个很小的值。所以你会在开始时加上这个
updated component get forward vector. So by doing this, we should be able to see two capsules
更新的分量得到向前的矢量。因此，通过这样做，我们应该能够看到两个胶囊
that are almost overlapping with each other. Since the forward vector here only has length
几乎是相互重叠的。因为这里的前向量只有长度
of one. All right, I'm going to fill in start, then fill in end. And as for the show debug
1的长度。好吧，我先填上开始，再填上结束。而对于显示调试
shape, I'm going to fill in true so that we can see what the shape is actually like. All
形状，我要填入true，这样我们就可以看到这个形状的实际情况了。好的
right, this is the function that we'll use to trace for climbable surfaces. But when
好的，这就是我们用来追踪可攀爬表面的函数。但是，什么时候
should we actually call this function? Well, for now, I'm going to call it inside of the
我们应该在什么时候真正调用这个函数呢？嗯，现在，我打算在
take function. So if you go to the header file of the component class, if you go to
函数中调用。所以，如果你去看组件类的头文件，如果你去看
the parent class, you character movement component. Instead of it, you can directly search for
父类，你的角色运动组件。而不是它，你可以直接搜索
take component. And you can see this is the function that we can use. So I'm going to
take组件。而且你可以看到这是我们可以使用的函数。所以我打算
copy this function. And I'm going to paste it back to our header file. So I'm going to
复制这个函数。我将把它粘贴到我们的头文件中。所以我将
create a public section for it. Then I'm going to create a function definition for this tick
为它创建一个公共部分。然后我将为这个tick创建一个函数定义
and place it above this client traces. And first thing I'm going to call the super version
的函数定义，并把它放在这个客户端痕迹的上面。首先，我将调用它的超级版本
of it. I'm going to copy of this and paste it in here and delete all the types. Then
它的超级版本。我将复制这个并粘贴到这里，然后删除所有的类型。然后
I'm going to call the function that I just created. So I'm going to copy this and paste
我将调用我刚刚创建的函数。所以我打算复制这个并粘贴
it in here. All right, that's pretty much it. I'm going to press control plus B to compile.
它在这里。好了，这就差不多了。我将按控制键加B来编译。
I have a successful compile. I'm going to press control plus F5 to launch my editor.
我有一个成功的编译。我将按下控制键加F5来启动我的编辑器。
All right, go inside of my editor. There's one more thing that we need to do. So I'm
好了，进入我的编辑器。还有一件事我们需要做。所以我将
going to open the blueprint class. Then I'm going to go inside of this custom moving component.
要打开蓝图类。然后我将进入这个自定义移动组件。
So you can see these are the variables that we created in the last lecture. And for this
所以你可以看到这些是我们在上次讲座中创建的变量。而对于这个
climbable surface type, I'm going to click add element. And this is the type that we'll
可攀爬表面类型，我将点击添加元素。这就是我们将
be tracing for static. All right, I'm going to press compile. Then I'm going to press
追踪静态的类型。好的，我将按下编译。然后我将按
play. And you can see this is the shape. Now if we run to the surfaces in here, you can
播放。你可以看到这就是形状。现在，如果我们运行到这里的表面，你可以看到我们得到了一次撞击。
see we get one hit. Since we're only tracing for static, if we run to this blue cube here,
你可以看到我们得到了一个结果。因为我们只追踪静态的东西，如果我们跑到这个蓝色的立方体上，就不会有任何结果、
we don't get a hit. And that's perfect. That is what we want. And since we are doing capsule
我们没有得到一个结果。这很完美。这就是我们想要的。由于我们在做胶囊
trace multi-fold objects, we can get hold of all the different surfaces in front of
追踪多重物体，我们可以掌握所有不同的表面，在我们面前
us. So inside of this level prototyping folder, meshes, I'm going to drag out different meshes.
我们。所以在这个水平原型文件夹里面，网格，我将拖出不同的网格。
So for this cube, I'm going to increase its size a little bit. So maybe three for the
所以对于这个立方体，我要把它的大小增加一点。因此，可能是3个X和5个Y，8个Y。
X and five for the Y and eight for the Z. And now if I duplicate this shape, rotate it a
现在，如果我复制这个形状，把它旋转一下，变成这样。
little bit to something like this. And if I press play, now if I go to the surface here,
变成这样的东西。如果我按下播放键，现在如果我转到这里的表面、
you can see I get two hit results. And this will be extremely useful later for our calculation
你可以看到我得到了两个结果。这对我们以后的计算将非常有用。
when we are climbing. Later when you implement this by yourself, so we can use the updated
当我们在爬坡时。以后当你自己实现了这一点，那么我们就可以用更新的
component to get hold of all the important information that we need. And don't forget
组件来掌握所有我们需要的重要信息。而且别忘了
to add in the trace type inside of Character Blueprint in order to get the correct hit
在角色蓝图中加入跟踪类型，以便得到正确的打击结果。
result. Alright, time for you to set up your own Climb Trace and I'll see you in the next
结果。好了，是时候让你建立你自己的攀爬跟踪了，我们在下一节课上见。
lecture.
讲座。
[Music]
[音乐]